So I was browsing reddit, and this new CTF for beginners popped up.
显然，我必须检查它，然后直接进入我最喜欢的类别，二进制开发
stuff.
当然，有一个服务器可以作为普通用户连接，当您利用
您将向另一个用户提升权限以访问机密的挑战
flag.
但最大的挑战是，我找不到禁止这样做的规则
to gain root.
So let’s do that.
还记得我的脏母牛解释视频吗？
让我们使用我们在那里的概念验证工具，并测试它是否适用于此
server.
So we can simply copy this code to a file in tmp and compile it.
测试是否可以覆盖不属于我们的文件，而不覆盖关键文件
根拥有的文件，我们作为系统上的另一个挑战用户登录，创建一个包含
content.
然后我们返回到第一个用户，对该文件执行dirty cow并尝试写入
some other characters to it.
And when we check, we can see that it works.
此时，我在Reddit上给作者写了一条消息，通知他服务器是
vulnerable and he should quickly update.
But now we need a plan what root file we could overwrite to become root ourselves.
我们的限制是，我们必须覆盖文件中的某些内容，我们不能追加或
prepend anything.
第一个明显的想法是使用setuid二进制文件，但问题是为了编写一个
从后门shell到二进制文件，我们必须解析elf文件格式并找出
where the entry point is.
An easier strategy is to overwrite data in a text file.
And I chose /etc/passwd.
您可以在这里看到用户的用户ID，如果我们要更改pwn1的uid
user to 0, we would login as root.
So.
The dirty cow proof of concept writes to the beginning of the file.
So first we have to figure out the offset inside of /etc/passwd.
We can use hexdump for that and count a little bit.
So pwn1 user is at offset hex 4c0 plus a little bit.
I use python as a caluclator and modify the exploit code to write to a fixed offset.
I think here would be a good plan.
你必须非常小心地选择这些补偿和选择什么
write, because you can screw up the whole system if you don’t.
So I copy /etc/passwd to try what I want to do before doing it to the real binary.
And of course, my first attempt would have wrecked the system.
因此，稍微调整偏移量，并在末尾附加新行，最终是成功的。
and I write to the real /etc/passwd.
Now when we switch to pwn1 or ssh login to pwn1, we get a root shell.
Then we can read out all flags.
Once we are done, we revert back /etc/passwd to the original state.
Some important notes.
Be very very careful what you overwrite with an exploit like this.
只有一个字节计算错误，您可能会使系统不稳定、崩溃、DOS或
lock yourself out.
Also if you find a server vulnerable, think about the impact or context you are in.
这个小的私有CTF服务器项目，打算被锤击，不同于
a webserver you exploited from some random company.
因此，如果您没有权限或可能导致
damage.
Make an ethical decision.
Be aware of the risk you are taking.
And thanks to maro for being cool about this and allowing me to make a video about it.
Good luck with your plattform.